Don't let anyone tell you what it is.
Catfish is a documentary film directed by Ariel Schulman.
Nev, a 24-year-old New York-based photographer, has no idea what he's in for when Abby, an eight-year-old girl
from rural Michigan, contacts him on Facebook, seeking permission to paint one of his photographs.
When he receives her remarkable painting, Nev begins a
friendship and correspondence with Abby's family.
But things really get interesting when he develops a cyber-romance with
Abby's attractive older sister, Megan, a musician and model.
Prompted by some startling revelations about Megan, Nev and his
buddies embark on a road trip in search of the truth.
Self, played by Nēv Schulman.
Self, played by Ariel Schulman.
Self, played by Angela Wesselman-Pierce.
Self, played by Melody C. Roscher.
Self, played by Henry Joost.
Dancer: Morphoses, played by Wendy Whelan.
Catfish is a 2010 American documentary film directed
by Henry Joost and Ariel Schulman.
It involves a young man, Nev, being filmed by his brother and friend, co-directors Ariel and Henry, as he
builds a romantic relationship with a young woman on the social networking website Facebook.
The film was a critical and commercial success.
It led to an MTV reality TV series, Catfish: The TV Show.
The film is credited with coining the term catfishing: a type of deceptive activity involving
a person creating a fake social networking presence for nefarious purposes.
The film explores themes of dating, found footage,
aftercreditsstinger, online dating.